<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause id="_6ee9086f-5ebc-429d-842d-8d0e6ba39533" outputclass="ncc-clause"><meta><facet building="Class 2"/><facet building="Class 3"/><facet building="Class 4"/><facet building="Class 5"/><facet building="Class 6"/><facet building="Class 7a"/><facet building="Class 7b"/><facet building="Class 8"/><facet building="Class 9a"/><facet building="Class 9b"/><facet building="Class 9c"/><facet building="Class 10a"/><facet building="Class 10b"/><facet building="Class 10c"/></meta><sptc>11.3.7</sptc><title id="_fcf56754-42df-4805-9b4a-fd8add97d47a">Protection of openable windows – bedrooms</title><archive-num>2019: 3.9.2.6</archive-num><subclause id="_b2e951a2-e13d-4ea7-a5c5-9c71e7e3adb0" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_df1dd2f2-ce05-4f3a-98fc-9c30c052e1aa">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p>A window opening in a bedroom must be provided with protection, where the floor below the window is 2 m or more above the surface beneath.</p></subclause><subclause id="_dbf0c11b-f5d5-45cd-afc2-45d437bcb7fd" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_16d521b7-1e7f-4818-b38c-707b7972cd78">SubClause</title><num>2</num><p>Where the lowest level of the window opening covered by (1) is less than 1.7 m above the floor, the window opening must comply with the following:</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_43fac392-0d10-414e-aadd-ea4ad6000e20">The openable portion of the window must be protected with—<ol><li>a device capable of restricting the window opening; or</li><li>a screen with secure fittings.</li></ol></li><li id="_ac68f8a6-3e26-410f-957a-cb8e9f392d7c">A device or screen <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1432_4.0.0.xml#_af6fde9f-147d-4782-8b85-42044e80fd42" id="_0907f805-f375-4268-97bc-24ddb3bcb761" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">required</xref> by (a) must—<ol><li>not permit a 125 mm sphere to pass through the window opening or screen; and</li><li>resist an outward horizontal action of 250 N against the—<ol><li>window restrained by a device; or</li><li>screen protecting the opening; and</li></ol></li><li>have a child resistant release mechanism if the screen or device is able to be removed, unlocked or overridden.</li></ol></li></ol></subclause><subclause id="_268354ca-30a1-4a96-832c-85d1b74644bc" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_79539290-cc12-4808-8850-fdd4197e9922">SubClause</title><num>3</num><p>Where a device or screen provided in accordance with (2)(a) is able to be removed, unlocked or overridden, a barrier with a height not less than 865 mm above the floor is <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1432_4.0.0.xml#_af6fde9f-147d-4782-8b85-42044e80fd42" id="_4c278a55-0167-4d54-b3ba-fd40fbd0a0e9" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">required</xref> to an openable window in addition to window protection.</p></subclause><subclause id="_74c4b386-f6d5-4012-8404-e78afb9a1a7e" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_6c0709bd-2fd7-4dfb-bb80-5ef432b9a1ec">SubClause</title><num>4</num><p>A barrier covered by (3) must not—</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_e7e63e34-2561-4fa5-bc1b-be1a3653c0b5">permit a 125 mm sphere to pass through it; and</li><li id="_44bd66e4-bc9c-4f4d-bf39-a13e5aa6c24a">have any horizontal or near horizontal elements between 150 mm and 760 mm above the floor that facilitate climbing (see <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/890_0.7.0.xml#_9568653a-86bc-444e-9900-1939ee10af49" id="_cb8777fc-9f20-4763-b91e-76e369ae5d95" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="image-reference">Figure 11.3.7</xref>).</li></ol></subclause><image-reference conref="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/890_0.7.0.xml" id="_9568653a-86bc-444e-9900-1939ee10af49"><num/><title id="_3c8d2c52-dc49-476a-84b8-1409ae487956"/></image-reference><callout id="_8b4ee115-b6ce-432d-8006-8a75e90960cb"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><title id="_a1610452-df5a-450f-9215-18790151f498">Intent</title><p>The intent of 11.3.7 is to reduce the risk of a person (especially a young child) falling through an openable window.</p></callout><callout id="_e067acae-fe4a-4b50-aa7a-24b5eb12944a"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><title id="_5c5590f6-417a-4196-ab1c-7e3bfb076563">Protection of openable windows – bedrooms</title><p>Where the floor level below an openable window in a bedroom is less than 2 m there are no specific requirements. For an openable window 2 m or more above the surface beneath, openable windows are <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1432_4.0.0.xml#_af6fde9f-147d-4782-8b85-42044e80fd42" id="_9ac76a02-4845-47c1-805b-0b27baff8dd7" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">required</xref> to restrict passage of a 125 mm sphere using any one of the following design solutions: </p><ul outputclass="alpha"><li>The window be designed such that any opening does not allow a 125 mm sphere to pass through (e.g. louvres) and be capable of resisting a 250 N force when directed against the window.</li><li>The window be fitted with a fixed or dynamic device that is capable of restricting the window opening so it does not allow a 125 mm sphere to pass through and is difficult for a young child to operate. The restricting device must be capable of resisting a 250 N force when directed against the window such as a casement window or in attempting to push a sliding window open. An internal screen with similar parameters may be installed.</li><li>The window be fitted with an internal or external screen that does not allow a 125 mm sphere to pass through and which must resist a horizontal outward force of 250 N.</li></ul><p>If the openable part of the window is at least 1.7 m above the floor, no further protection is <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1432_4.0.0.xml#_af6fde9f-147d-4782-8b85-42044e80fd42" id="_d247de24-bde4-45bc-af37-50ecc826d715" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">required</xref>.</p></callout><callout id="_54e07a90-e073-45bc-829c-ad2ca8e121e9"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><title id="_6dfb29e6-4306-493e-95e3-921a2a075ab3">Restricting devices</title><p>Where a device or screen is securely fixed in position (e.g. a screen pop riveted to the window frame) so it cannot be unlocked, overridden, or is very difficult to remove without for example a drill, the 865 mm barrier would not be <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1432_4.0.0.xml#_af6fde9f-147d-4782-8b85-42044e80fd42" id="_168f1131-a247-4c26-a667-a6c508f50d66" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">required</xref> as the securing method is considered a fixture and not a child resistant release mechanism. 11.3.7(2)(b)(iii) relates to a screen or window restricting device protecting an openable window in a bedroom. The screen or opening restricting device may be installed in a manner that allows it to be removed, unlocked or overridden in the event of a fire or other emergency to allow safe egress. In these situations the unlocking device must be child resistant.</p><p>Child resistance could be achieved by the need to use a tool, key or two hands.</p><p>There are a number of hardware options available. Short chain winders and barrier screens will allow windows to comply with this requirement. Sliding window locks may lock a sash so a 125 mm sphere cannot pass through. Where provision is made to fully open the window beyond 125 mm then the child resistant release mechanism is required in addition to the device resisting a 250 N force as <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1432_4.0.0.xml#_af6fde9f-147d-4782-8b85-42044e80fd42" id="_344c4b98-5d35-4d1f-9687-b57da9bc6f8a" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">required</xref> by 11.3.7(2)(b)(ii).</p><p>11.3.7 in addition prescribes that an 865 mm barrier (sill) would be <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1432_4.0.0.xml#_af6fde9f-147d-4782-8b85-42044e80fd42" id="_fba27224-73c4-4d6d-836f-8ee8041ee35a" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">required</xref>. A wall beneath an openable window or fixed glazing under the openable part of a window which meets the height requirements (e.g. transom at least 865 mm above the floor) can be considered as the barrier if the criteria in 11.3.7 are met.</p></callout><callout id="_17b3167c-3144-45b0-82c4-cebc8d310407"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><title id="_cdfbbe53-9db5-4e2e-85c5-482e0599ed24">Use of the term ‘window’</title><p>The term “window” is not italicised in 11.3.7 and as such, is not restricted to the definition of “window” in the NCC. The reason for this is to also capture windows that may let in air but not light, e.g. metal louvres. A metal louvre or openable panel would not fit in the NCC definition of window but is subject to the window barrier provisions.</p></callout></clause>