<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-part" ?><part xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" id="_2d24827b-54cf-4c66-b8b1-4c1745b963ad" outputclass="ncc-part"><num>A3</num><title id="_4f536d7f-8c37-48d9-bb21-5f3112cda61c">Application of the NCC in States and Territories</title><intro-part id="_9644a0df-0545-42e6-ba62-f5fcb6c41cef"><p>This Part explains applying the NCC in accordance with State or Territory legislation. The NCC has legal effect through references in relevant State or Territory building and plumbing legislation.</p><p>Although the NCC is a nationally consistent code, there are some situations where a State or Territory enforces a variation, addition or deletion to it. This Part also explains how these variations, additions and deletions apply.</p></intro-part><subtopic id="_a7738227-6974-4774-869f-00c356340dc3" subtopic-type="governance"><clauseref id="_4c6a8f2b-11d3-49fa-81c5-260408d830ff" outputclass="clausref-ncc"><clause author="Raymond Elworthy" conref="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/4501_0.6.0.xml" dateTime="2020-11-20T13:32:06" id="_7ce7255b-f946-459a-b2ae-7091961ca2a1" outputclass="ncc-clause" type="insert"><sptc/><title id="_5398fe4f-a05d-421b-a571-7095d2e471f4"/><archive-num/></clause></clauseref></subtopic><callout id="_0aee4759-5dbb-4cbd-8274-561ee26631a5"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><p>The NCC is given legal effect by building regulatory legislation in each State and Territory. This legislation consists of an Act of Parliament and subordinate legislation which empowers the regulation of certain aspects of building and plumbing, and contains the administrative provisions necessary to give effect to the legislation.</p><p>Although the NCC is a national code, in some instances it is necessary for a State or Territory to vary or apply additional requirements specific to their jurisdiction. A3G1(2) highlights that these variations, additions or deletions must be applied in conjunction with the NCC provisions. Typically, these variations, additions or deletions override the requirements contained within the NCC.</p><p>Any provision of the NCC may be overridden by, or subject to, State or Territory legislation. The NCC must therefore be read in conjunction with that legislation. Any queries on such matters should be referred to the State or Territory authority responsible for building and plumbing regulatory matters.</p><p>Where a requirement or provision of the NCC is subject to a State or Territory variation, addition, or deletion, a reference to the appropriate provision in the applicable State or Territory schedule is included with that requirement or provision.</p></callout></part>