<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause id="_00b3f931-804a-4e9d-ab68-e46968a51f62" outputclass="ncc-clause"><meta><facet building="Class 1a"/><facet building="Class 1b"/><facet building="Class 2"/><facet building="Class 3"/><facet building="Class 4"/><facet building="Class 5"/><facet building="Class 6"/><facet building="Class 7a"/><facet building="Class 7b"/><facet building="Class 8"/><facet building="Class 10a"/><facet building="Class 10b"/><facet building="Class 10c"/></meta><sptc>A6G10</sptc><title id="_dc64c311-e88e-4c45-b52a-bf4ea69e4af6">Class 9 buildings</title><archive-num>2019: A6.9</archive-num><subclause id="_22280070-72ad-44fd-a227-cdb53eed5c6f" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_9f5b0aa7-608b-4a59-a07d-1d5107287505">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p>A Class 9 building is a building of a public nature.</p></subclause><subclause id="_29600def-d328-4cf9-a42d-40d32b5cf2f1" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_7de3b916-d8a3-4465-92db-4bb9dc781bf2">SubClause</title><num>2</num><p>Class 9 includes the following sub-classifications:</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_da736742-326b-46c0-ae6b-0abc6279edc8">Class 9a — a <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1333_0.4.0.xml#_1f5fbee8-584a-4244-9286-ebf9d8ebb04a" id="_a82507bd-93dc-4b43-960d-cf7bf51a6ac8" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">health-care building</xref> including any parts of the building set aside as laboratories, and includes a <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1333_0.4.0.xml#_1f5fbee8-584a-4244-9286-ebf9d8ebb04a" id="_d11a3793-dc94-4deb-9dce-5f5154df8f1b" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">health-care building</xref> used as a <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1436_4.0.0.xml#_b286ccd1-342e-49e1-95e9-4b6a0a6c0447" id="_482cd8ba-84d4-46e8-9a73-7d24eed5e719" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">residential care building</xref>.</li><li id="_f37fc35d-3fdd-4d4a-aa5f-865aff7110cf">Class 9b — an <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1195_1.0.0.xml#_367d20c3-85f7-45e8-ad37-bba3e069f07d" id="_e52d9e6e-37d9-4879-9540-21e03e445093" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">assembly building</xref> including a trade workshop or laboratory in a primary or secondary <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1447_0.6.0.xml#_23515733-4511-421a-8c89-650d33e5f6e4" id="_a095e25e-4b11-473b-9d14-bd395eb867fa" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">school</xref>.</li><li id="_0b80c3dd-fee4-4fd1-8a74-97923dfe77c9">Class 9c — a <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1436_4.0.0.xml#_b286ccd1-342e-49e1-95e9-4b6a0a6c0447" id="_b5389705-4343-4291-8b69-b542609f012d" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">residential care building</xref>.</li></ol></subclause><callout id="_636df5aa-a81e-4de5-bae9-854a2e1b7e46"><callout-type ncc-info-type="exemption"/><p>A6G10(2)(b) excludes any parts of the building that are of another Class.</p></callout><callout id="_4124b5ab-37dd-4369-adac-d70bd9237e1a"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><p>Class 9a buildings are <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1333_0.4.0.xml#_1f5fbee8-584a-4244-9286-ebf9d8ebb04a" id="_80a6ba2b-9980-41ef-9194-bf7c89984620" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">health-care buildings</xref>, including day-care surgeries or procedure units and the like. See definition of <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1333_0.4.0.xml#_1f5fbee8-584a-4244-9286-ebf9d8ebb04a" id="_bff802c8-519e-4b81-95e4-ec4d33542cb9" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">health-care building</xref>. Laboratories that are part of a Class 9a building are Class 9a, despite the general classification of laboratories as Class 8 buildings.</p><p>Class 9b buildings are <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1195_1.0.0.xml#_367d20c3-85f7-45e8-ad37-bba3e069f07d" id="_05fd33ef-e77b-4c01-bfdf-e27035d7b8ed" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">assembly buildings</xref>.</p><p>These buildings can include—</p><ul><li>theatres, cinemas and halls, churches, schools, early childhood centres, kindergartens, preschools and child-minding centres; and</li><li>indoor cricket, tennis, basketball centres and sport stadiums; and</li><li>nightclubs, discotheques, bar areas providing live entertainment and/or containing a dance floor, public halls, dance halls and other places of entertainment; and</li><li>snooker halls; and</li><li>bus and railway stations.</li></ul><p>Regarding the Exemption to A6G10(2)(b), a building could be a mixture of Class 9b and another class, or a Class 9b building could contain parts that are of another class, but be taken as a Class 9b building because of Exemption (1) to <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/2522_1.14.0.xml#_0ee35551-9925-4c59-b6f9-964ad148124f" id="_2495ee35-437a-475d-91bc-cb6d7fdf1907" scope="local" type="clause">A6G1</xref>.</p><p>Class 9c buildings are <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1436_4.0.0.xml#_b286ccd1-342e-49e1-95e9-4b6a0a6c0447" id="_f101f403-b93c-4647-a44f-1d0bd309924a" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">residential care buildings</xref> that may contain residents who have various care level needs.</p><p>The Class 9c classification recognises that many residents progress through a continuum of care needs from low to high. Many older people enter residential care with low care needs (typically Class 3 facilities) but, as they age, require higher levels of care. In the past, such progression often necessitated the transfer of a hostel resident (Class 3) to a nursing home (Class 9a). This frequently had negative consequences for the health and well-being of the resident, for whom the hostel accommodation was home. It also led, at times, to the separation of couples with differing care needs.</p><p>Building designers should note that Class 3 buildings include hostels for the accommodation of the aged, and Class 9a buildings include nursing homes. It is important to be aware, however, that construction of Class 3 or 9a buildings may restrict the options available to the operators of a facility in relation to the profile of the residents they wish to accommodate. Where the potential exists for residents of varying care needs to be accommodated, consideration of the Class 9c provisions may be appropriate. The Class 9c classification allows for any mix of low and high care residents and is intended to allow the mix to change as the residents' care needs change over time, without the need to obtain any further consent or approval from the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1189_0.7.0.xml#_c1612e09-903f-47de-9ee0-00fb915ae751" id="_828572a4-9cbc-4cc9-96a0-a80526e9be3e" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">appropriate authority</xref>.</p><p>Multi-care level facilities are for residents who may require the full range of care services outlined by the Aged Care Act. Hence, it is not intended to restrict the resident type and provides maximum flexibility for service providers, residents and the community.</p><p>The NCC provisions for Class 9c buildings are based on minimal on duty on-site staff being available at any time. However, it is recognised that the staff numbers vary throughout the course of any one day, due to the care needs of the residents and the functioning of the facility. It is also recognised that the specific care needs of the residents may result in a greater minimum number of staff.</p></callout></clause>