<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause id="_fd0ae576-d2db-4e44-9b77-15ee44dc6f1a" outputclass="ncc-clause"><meta><facet building="Class 1a"/><facet building="Class 1b"/><facet building="Class 2"/><facet building="Class 4"/><facet building="Class 5"/><facet building="Class 6"/><facet building="Class 7a"/><facet building="Class 7b"/><facet building="Class 8"/><facet building="Class 9a"/><facet building="Class 9b"/><facet building="Class 9c"/><facet building="Class 10a"/><facet building="Class 10b"/><facet building="Class 10c"/></meta><sptc>A6G4</sptc><title id="_96c1cddd-e76f-428c-acc8-34b29656a6f3">Class 3 buildings</title><archive-num>2019: A6.3</archive-num><subclause id="_4acdb74c-d875-4943-a019-a9a9992ae88f" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_4560f5c3-3002-4d5e-9722-e6db9cd94bb9">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p>A Class 3 building is a residential building providing long-term or transient accommodation for a number of unrelated persons.</p></subclause><subclause id="_f3b6db2c-62dd-47a8-a59b-60481bf686f8" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_18d198b7-bd14-41ce-8220-ad69bc1c3bbb">SubClause</title><num>2</num><p>Class 3 buildings include the following:</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_01afa9dd-260d-4ba4-9f62-9f233babc5af">A boarding house, guest house, hostel, lodging house or backpacker accommodation.</li><li id="_46d25fe5-f927-46b8-a3be-3278fcf56428">A residential part of a hotel or motel.</li><li id="_6f31bade-006c-4f7e-b0fe-7a0b54993424">A residential part of a <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1447_0.6.0.xml#_23515733-4511-421a-8c89-650d33e5f6e4" id="_463b9b55-8fad-4ac9-9713-cb7ede1f7ff0" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">school</xref>.</li><li id="_237690fe-6877-4d5b-805b-0ed30bc29d9c">Accommodation for the aged, children, or people with disability.</li><li id="_9bef7d98-19e2-4fe2-8d7c-e928aaa1bcb7">A residential part of a <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1333_0.4.0.xml#_1f5fbee8-584a-4244-9286-ebf9d8ebb04a" id="_38993dbb-c6dd-4d63-a4b3-5f61c57b9a54" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">health-care building</xref> which accommodates members of staff.</li><li id="_68173add-86da-4f80-819d-2b727f11b988">A residential part of a <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1244_0.7.0.xml#_32cca056-7f6e-4135-b2e2-ce403cac23e7" id="_b425d3c2-18c6-4984-8893-77a584e48115" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">detention centre</xref>.</li><li id="_cf69edec-ffb3-40d2-8b51-ec412ca7027d">A <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1436_4.0.0.xml#_b286ccd1-342e-49e1-95e9-4b6a0a6c0447" id="_225d580f-bd71-4e79-ad96-0aafb9f58cdf" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">residential care building</xref>.</li></ol></subclause><callout id="_fedc20e2-5cb7-470a-bf28-63df3fa3ca51"><callout-type ncc-info-type="limitation"/><p>For A6G4, a Class 3 building is not a Class 1 or 2 building but may be a mixture of Class 3 and another class.</p></callout><callout id="_8896e4a5-988b-4f1d-ad66-f8f638e54819"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><p>Class 3 buildings provide accommodation for unrelated people. The length of stay is unimportant.</p><p>Some exceptions to this classification include: certain bed and breakfast accommodation, boarding houses, guest houses, hostels, or lodging houses and the like which fall within the concession provided for Class 1b buildings.</p><p>Also, any sized building can be classified as Class 1 or Class 2 if it is used to house any number of unrelated people who jointly own or rent it, or share it on a non-rental basis with an owner or tenant.</p><p>It is not unusual for a manager’s, owner’s or caretaker’s dwelling attached to a Class 3 building to be thought of as a Class 4 part of the Class 3 building. However, a Class 4 part of a building can only be part of a Class 5-9 building.</p><p>Accordingly, such dwellings are either classified as Class 1, Class 2 or Class 3, depending on the circumstances of the building proposal. However, a building could be a mixture of Class 3 and another class.</p><p>Class 3 buildings include—</p><ul><li>the residential parts of hotels and motels; and</li><li>hotel or motel caretakers’, managers’ or owners’ flats, noting that under certain circumstances such dwellings could be Class 1, Class 2 or Class 3 buildings; and</li><li>dormitory accommodation, in schools or elsewhere, noting that a dormitory is generally (but not always) considered to be a <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1473_0.4.0.xml#_d2c89488-8a36-464b-94f6-a91d0f5a6c9c" id="_52265eb7-a0d6-4edd-b486-80f189d7af8f" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">sole-occupancy unit</xref>; and</li><li>bed and breakfast accommodation, a boarding house, guest house, hostel, or lodging house; and</li><li>backpackers’ accommodation; and</li><li>a building which houses elderly people or other people who require special care (in some States or Territories it is not acceptable for a Class 1b building to be used to house elderly people or other people who require special care - it is recommended the local building regulatory body be consulted); and</li><li>workers’ quarters, including shearers’ or fruit pickers’ accommodation, or hotel workers’ accommodation.</li></ul></callout></clause>