<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" id="_f79aab68-e5ec-407d-8047-74f6544ee90a" outputclass="ncc-clause"><sptc>B1P1</sptc><title id="_295d5d1e-d560-4fbf-bc7b-bdf84f377e21">Cold water supply</title><archive-num>2019: BP1.1</archive-num><subclause id="_3201c08d-076f-4a8d-9338-f7045695bca1" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_b20a2c56-30fd-440c-82c3-348899a97f96">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p>A cold water service must be connected to a <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1250_0.7.0.xml#_762d6a54-e28c-400b-b9c5-5fceac019a05" id="_208de86f-c97e-43e7-8626-f7c0f7867876" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">drinking water</xref> supply.</p></subclause><callout id="_02bb1699-0c6f-4609-ab93-de515516b603"><callout-type ncc-info-type="application"/><ol outputclass="numbered"><li id="_6f07f215-70a9-46f3-a105-feb47d84aa51">B1P1 applies to cold water supplied for human consumption, food preparation, food utensil washing or personal hygiene.</li><li id="_e0fde486-b97c-48ed-8ccd-b1860484b00a">B1P1 applies to automatic fire sprinkler systems when installed in accordance with FPAA101D Automatic Fire Sprinkler System Design and Installation - Drinking Water Supply.</li></ol></callout><callout id="_ce389895-418f-4579-bdc4-265d92d2398d"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><title id="_7eada2fe-b146-4edb-b9e4-87d7919323a7">Unintentional heating of cold water services</title><ul outputclass="numbered"><li>Where installed in a location subjected to extreme summer temperatures (such as the roof space of a building), cold water services have the potential to become unintentionally heated. This can pose a hazard as the cold water supply may reach temperatures in excess of 45° Celsius, increasing the potential for scalding. </li><li>To reduce the likelihood of unintentional heating of cold water services, consideration should be given to—<ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_cfef8fbd-a573-4ec5-832d-52001ec67b88">avoiding long runs of pipework in locations exposed to solar heat gain; or</li><li>applying insulation, either directly to the pipework, or by using additional ceiling insulation material between the pipework and the solar heat source.</li></ol></li><li>Avoidance of unintentional heating of cold water services in known areas of extreme summer temperatures may also assist in reducing water usage through drawing off of water which has become excessively heated.</li></ul></callout></clause>