<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause id="_bdd29989-48e8-469a-a703-2d6e7fc48903" outputclass="ncc-clause" variation="VIC"><sptc>C1D3</sptc><title id="_bd1c705a-6599-40bc-ad97-41f19e3df862">General requirements</title><archive-num>2019: VIC C1.3</archive-num><subclause id="_ba761d17-73ad-4c87-8716-1fef47c8f63c" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_3b852a24-0f2c-4918-8375-c1183e88747a">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p>A sanitary <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1401_0.7.0.xml#_a318c0f3-5635-4ac0-b103-59d798c9f23d" id="_f7d4387c-400d-470f-8fd8-1221481f9b95" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">plumbing</xref> system must be in accordance with AS/NZS 3500.2 subject to the following: </p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_07a87e6a-859a-4616-bbfc-324669eacd8e">For Class 1 buildings, substitute Clause 6.6.2.4.2 as follows:<ol><li>6.6.2.4.2 New installations: Where a junction is used to make the connection of a DN 100 branch pipe to another DN 100 pipe, the entry level of the branch pipe shall be elevated at an incline of not less than 15° above the horizontal. Where the 15° requirement cannot be achieved, the incline must be as close as possible to 15° to avoid stranding. Where a fixture is connected to a graded discharge pipe, the installation shall also be in accordance with Clause 6.6.2.1.</li></ol></li><li id="_3a70c96f-7aa9-4b4d-9a4d-b5d619a57df4">After clause 13.9(b), delete the following: Where a bath trap is not accessible, the bath shall discharge untrapped to a floor waste gully (FWG) in accordance with Table 4.6.7.2 and Appendix B.</li><li id="_7df0de5c-62fc-4660-8f40-0908ba07fa85">After clause 15.1, insert clause 15.1A as follows: When tested, the respective sections of any soil pipe, waste pipe, vent pipe or above-ground drain must be free of leaks when subjected to an air test in accordance with clause 15.3.</li><li id="_485eb6bd-96a5-4b98-8f9e-40088b272b6c">Substitute clause 15.3.3 as follows: When tested, the respective sections of any soil pipe, waste pipe, vent pipe or above ground drain must be free of leaks when subjected to an air test in accordance with clause 15.3.2 over the minimum test duration specified in Table 15.3.2.</li></ol></subclause></clause>