<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause id="_5992991f-654d-4424-8fc5-62ad76718191" outputclass="ncc-clause" variation="VIC"><sptc>E2D2</sptc><title id="_5e3397ae-dd98-41fd-abb3-348126b04c71">General requirements</title><archive-num>2019: G1.2</archive-num><subclause id="_a3b27276-2169-47e2-b3c8-0b57e5a57e6e" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_4892cf5b-e1a5-40f6-8ffc-0834d3f6c8ba">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p>Mechanical ventilation and air-conditioning systems for buildings and structures must comply with the requirements of the relevant Parts of:</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_ddf8f929-086f-4367-a669-d2560c0d9f84">NCC Volume One for Class 2 to 9 Buildings; or</li><li id="_c0e3b798-4132-42b1-8189-b9852966723a">NCC Volume Two for Class 1 and 10 Buildings.</li></ol></subclause><subclause id="_7ed94329-34fd-452f-89b6-8e246c44dbb8" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_a2df71b4-b6f6-4a68-b703-3d3fa76dd440">SubClause</title><num>2</num><p>Mechanical ventilation and air-conditioning equipment must be in accordance with:</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_75f93ce4-8b08-43f6-a2f9-4f58986280aa">AS/NZS 1200 for the design, materials, manufacture, examination, testing, installation, commissioning, operation, inspection, maintenance, repair, alteration, and disposal of pressure equipment,</li><li id="_4f601238-ca90-40e3-9a02-40e28b61ea40">AS 1324.1 for the application, performance and construction for air filters for use in general ventilation and air-conditioning,</li><li id="_fa08f25d-6c44-49d8-abc8-9fa9ad283616">AS 1345 for the identification of the contents of pipes, conduits and ducts,</li><li id="_5f9e5993-7a8b-4d85-a8c0-8871ff114bcb">AS/NZS 1668.1 for the use of mechanical ventilation and air-conditioning in buildings for fire and smoke control in multi-compartment buildings,</li><li id="_ddbdea25-a812-40a7-960d-8bd4dcceff63">AS 1668.2 for the use of mechanical ventilation and air-conditioning in buildings for mechanical ventilation,</li><li id="_b7acbd59-3acf-41cb-bf90-3331890fbb5a">AS/NZS 3500.1 for the design, installation, alteration, addition, repair and commissioning of cold water services,</li><li id="_3f7cf1cb-ebe2-44b4-bf26-595489e33f27">AS/NZS 3500.2 for the design, installation, alteration, addition and repair of sanitary plumbing and drainage,</li><li id="_977a9c60-6698-48b6-a89f-29e131c181d5">AS/NZS 3500.4 for the design, installation, commissioning, alteration, addition and repair of heated water services,</li><li id="_58f2e7c7-49e2-4a0c-b2ff-6741ff8142b1">AS 4254.1 for flexible ductwork for air-handling systems in buildings,</li><li id="_fc658339-5eec-4ba2-8f85-c1fcd04d7475">AS 4254.2 for the rigid ductwork for air-handling systems in buildings,</li><li id="_2fd9f03b-003a-4f04-9ec1-609efbb91053">AS 4426 for the selection, installation and finish of thermal insulation of pipework, ductwork and equipment.</li><li id="_1229b876-863d-462c-a9c1-11b5504ac783">AS 4508 for the thermal resistance of insulation for ductwork used in building airconditioning, and</li><li id="_2deaeeb2-0f5f-45a9-9859-a510458350cf">AS/NZS 5141 for residential heating and cooling systems.</li><li id="_03ac413d-59a0-4e27-bdcf-fcc88ccd8f33">AS/NZS 5601.1 for gas installations.</li><li id="_dcea0a4c-25c9-495a-8427-f7b7959f05d4">AS 1271, AS 1358 and AS 4041 for the design, construction, installation, replacement, repair, alteration and maintenance of pressure equipment and piping.</li><li id="_21ee8a8d-1f28-4701-a154-109e6203e338">AS/NZS 4859.1 for thermal insulation of ductwork and pipework.</li><li id="_9794e60e-caaf-499f-a6ce-9488e50978a4">HB 276 for the design, supply, installation, testing and commissioning of mechanical ventilation and air conditioning systems in class 1, 2, 3 and 4 buildings.</li><li id="_817016f0-d50c-49d1-99c9-1462cf56cdc3">AS/NZS ISO 817 in relation to assigning designations for refrigerants used in air conditioning systems.</li><li id="_81126197-ae36-4eb6-bd53-4b144993336c">AS/NZS 5149.1, AS/NZS 5149.2, AS/NZS 5149.3 and AS/NZS 5149.4 for the design, construction, installation, testing, commissioning, operation, maintenance, repair and safety of refrigeration systems (including heat pumps) and recovery, reuse and disposal of refrigerants.</li><li id="_7e159ec0-08b5-45c9-b9f5-eb9ca2fa5e9c">Australian and New Zealand Refrigerant handling code of practice 2007 Part 1 for selfcontained low charged refrigeration systems.</li><li id="_6a1da074-9e7b-4c77-8d8e-db2028c49d9c">Australian and New Zealand Refrigerant handling code of practice 2007 Part 2 forsystems other than self- contained low charged systems.</li></ol></subclause><subclause id="_12fd46ee-5193-477e-bd19-82aa9ce75386" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_46951387-df07-4178-9ea2-7264bb3f712d">SubClause</title><num>3</num><p>Copper piping for air-conditioning and refrigeration must meet the requirements of AS/NZS 1571.</p></subclause><subclause id="_520d796e-4d41-48f8-8194-d02e17029636" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_9b2c5f11-a10f-441a-94bb-16283ad1adf1">SubClause</title><num>4</num><p>Microbial control must be carried out in accordance with AS/NZS 3666.1 and AS/NZS 3666.2 as appropriate.</p></subclause><subclause id="_308c6b4e-8bc7-41a3-bef5-4135b98c0e15" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_b8e38610-d27a-4a38-a4bd-3a750da2ffba">SubClause</title><num>5</num><p>Condensate drains and bleed down drains installed in heating, cooling and air-conditioning equipment (including evaporative coolers) other than cooling towers must discharge to any of the following—</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_fb9229fe-5945-4ac1-8b67-e502305524f9">an evaporative tray if specified by the manufacturer; or</li><li id="_77382537-dbb6-420b-9a61-f1cb851a4013">a sanitary drainage system by way of an untrapped tundish discharging to a charged floor waste gully in accordance with clause 4.6.7.8 or tundish and self-sealing device in accordance with clause 13.21 of AS/NZS 3500.2; or</li><li id="_39fb36dd-6364-4c25-bd15-be33d51a3fb2">a surface water drainage system; or</li><li id="_bfd5f433-0d4d-4a11-84ee-992381120f72">an absorption pit, but only if a sanitary or surface water drainage system is not available and the discharge water will not cause damage to buildings or facilities by changing soil moisture conditions.</li><li id="_b80752d7-c994-410f-8b60-ac6d56638f28">a stormwater downpipe directly over the connection to the roof gutter; or</li><li id="_806cfe11-acf6-4069-b670-5e708a9ef816">Directly to the stormwater downpipe below the connection to the roof gutter provided a means of overflow or reverse flow protection is incorporated; or</li><li id="_fd833905-a3d3-4285-9e6f-8021801980d3">for evaporative coolers only, over a tiled roof, by way of a spreader.</li></ol></subclause><subclause id="_0c990186-d228-40ab-b380-8f853f501e4a" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_bf2bd380-a0c8-4931-bbe6-0c6fd527b370">SubClause</title><num>6</num><p>Drains from a cooling tower must discharge to a sanitary drainage system in accordance with any applicable trade waste agreement.</p></subclause><subclause id="_8ce49dae-20ba-4da5-808c-90e762b23273" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_f3446b44-cfbf-4ae5-aec2-c176e41c7b9d">SubClause</title><num>7</num><p>Condensate drains and bleed down drains shall not discharge to a system that is used for the collection of water for potable use.</p></subclause><subclause id="_7f019612-3e50-45f7-9a2e-04fefbb2525c" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_fa4ea05c-0068-4037-bd8e-ed0b0bf31ed7">SubClause</title><num>8</num><p>In this clause, bleed down drain means a drain that collects fluid from a valve used for bleeding and purging; evaporative tray means a tray used to gather excess moisture or condensation for the purpose of evaporation.</p></subclause><subclause id="_96e049d7-2bd5-4a2b-bfb8-fda63ff5ba24" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_0d03b0ef-6bab-44b5-a576-2b3e870d8653">SubClause</title><num>9</num><p>Domestic solid fuel burning appliances must be in accordance with AS/NZS 2918.</p></subclause><subclause id="_a9c34a46-e586-42ce-9c98-b9163e4107d4" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_bcca7711-60d3-4663-b55b-2f1a01cab9f4">SubClause</title><num>10</num><p>Medical gas systems must be in accordance with AS 2896, AS 2473.3, AS 2568, and AS 2902.</p></subclause></clause>