<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" id="_4057371d-7155-444c-930f-4d858039e78f" outputclass="ncc-clause" variation="QLD"><meta><facet building="Class 2"/><facet building="Class 3"/><facet building="Class 4"/><facet building="Class 5"/><facet building="Class 6"/><facet building="Class 7a"/><facet building="Class 7b"/><facet building="Class 8"/><facet building="Class 9a"/><facet building="Class 9b"/><facet building="Class 9c"/></meta><sptc>H1P3</sptc><title id="_370b36d6-9b12-4ec3-ae74-33224df97070">Termite management measures</title><archive-num>2019: QLD P2.1.3</archive-num><subclause id="_777ad91e-d779-4c99-ac7e-03914cb64a56" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_688b646d-63d1-4bc7-b846-7f0c586c7d8c">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p>The risk of <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1406_0.16.0.xml#_5b1a07fa-ec9d-48a4-ad73-77cd5f362d25" id="_073fe236-9686-46c7-903d-8ebfb64b0060" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">primary building element</xref> in a Class 1 or 10 building being damaged by subterranean termites must be adequately minimised by the use of a suitable termite management measure that—</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_adb66aaa-e34c-4364-a4bc-abcafd781a96">if it serves a non-temporary Class 1 building, has a design life of at least 50 years; or</li><li id="_a20b9545-e51f-4c8b-8564-7aae8cd45f51">if it serves a building not specified in (a), has a design life of at least 50 years or the specified design life of the building, whichever is the lesser; or</li><li id="_6324f1fa-57e0-4536-bf54-f8894f0afc34">is easily and readily accessible for replenishment or replacement and is capable of being replenished or replaced.</li></ol></subclause><subclause id="_10083d4a-fdca-4dfb-9de1-7ab73ef0c41d" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_b58b1c51-2e44-4c85-b822-9f66f4003a6f">SubClause</title><num>2</num><p>A termite management measure <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1432_4.0.0.xml#_af6fde9f-147d-4782-8b85-42044e80fd42" id="_da7eca3d-53b7-47db-b22f-fd755e35a99d" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">required</xref> by (1), to the degree necessary, must—</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_a85b9d1e-9940-4447-8ef2-dc0a110f1ef1">be accessible to enable the installation, maintenance and inspection of the termite management measure to be carried out; and</li><li id="_dd8b58ab-21b8-400b-a803-f9fc1c4e3d0d">incorporate suitable measures to adequately minimise the risk of the termite management measure inadvertently being damaged, bridged or breached.</li></ol></subclause><callout id="_f3bbbee5-e086-4871-ad4d-5c3db4112edc"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><p>QLD H1P3(1) requires a termite management measure in Queensland to have a design life of at least 50 years unless it is easily and readily accessible for replenishment or replacement and is capable of being replenished or replaced. In recognition that some buildings other than non-temporary Class 1 buildings may be designed to last less than 50 years, the option of the termite management measure having a design life at least equal to that specified for the building is given. If this option is used, the design life of the building should be agreed upon by all relevant stakeholders at the design stage and should form part of the documentation kept by the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1189_0.7.0.xml#_c1612e09-903f-47de-9ee0-00fb915ae751" id="_b9c512f0-547d-47b2-a3ae-7e19a9ae4026" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">appropriate authority</xref>. It should not be assumed that the design life of 50 years in QLD H1P3(1)(a) and (b) applies to any other provisions of the BCA, unless stated.</p><p>An example of a termite management measure that may satisfy QLD H1P3(1)(c) is a chemical reticulation system beneath a concrete floor slab laid directly on the ground, provided that the system is easily and readily accessible for replenishment and is capable of being replenished.</p><p>An example of a termite management measure that may not satisfy QLD H1P3(1) for a non-temporary Class 1 building is a hand-sprayed chemical beneath a concrete floor slab laid directly on the ground if the chemical does not have a design life of at least 50 years. The concrete floor slab being laid directly on the ground would prevent the area beneath the slab from being easily and readily accessible for replenishment or replacement of the termite management measure.</p><p>An example of a termite management measure being inadvertently bridged or breached is when a person places a garden or mulch over the top of or above the level of a termite management measure enabling termites to bypass the measure.</p></callout></clause>