<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="page" ?><page id="_cf600737-c4a6-436d-8f6f-8e3b4cdc25af" outputclass="page"><title id="_861c8a17-5925-4601-8325-566b8de626b9">History of adoption of NCC Volume One</title><section id="_3284eab7-3a0f-41f5-b055-5cdc387290c8"><title id="_74d81793-050c-493c-8fba-9408b88b43b8">Adoption of NCC Volume One</title><p>The adoption of each edition of NCC Volume One (also referred to as BCA Volume One) is set out in Table 1.</p></section><table-reference conref="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/1533_0.15.0.xml" graph="None" id="_196ae0b4-2873-48a3-bcb3-92d3c571600b"><num/><title id="_8ab6643f-0bee-409f-aff5-897ecbe9fafc"/></table-reference><section id="_019a7d41-2b4e-44e2-af00-f619f2f44132" keep-with-next="true"><title id="_202cd3ce-1139-42c4-a157-ac82a87ff326" outputclass="none" toc="true">Adoption of BCA 96 Volume One</title><p>The 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p></section><section id="_3504cbb9-8e53-4747-9602-1adbd7cb98d0"><title id="_9e8a13d0-2649-47f3-8ccc-5bb431b28efa">BCA 96 Amendment No. 1</title><p>Amendment No. 1 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 1 is to—</p><ul><li>correct minor typographical errors including spelling, punctuation and layout; and</li><li>include reference to a Certificate of Conformity issued by the ABCB in A2.2; and</li><li>change the reference to the Standards Mark Certificate to refer to JAS–ANZ in A2.2; and</li><li>update references to Standards</li></ul><p>Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_4ccee4a2-d62b-4a0a-822b-cd8159ab1a8c"><title id="_e39da135-5c7f-4e74-8260-56bf2efb8b56">BCA 96 Amendment No. 2</title><p>Amendment No. 2 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 2 is to—</p><ul><li>correct minor typographical errors; and</li><li>update references to Standards.</li></ul></section><section id="_67735090-0dd6-4346-8dc0-45f1ab5a8d85"><title id="_de67fd0f-0a4b-4388-ba61-7a5069869260">BCA 96 Amendment No. 3</title><p>Amendment No. 3 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 3 is to—</p><ul><li>incorporate the outcomes of the 1997 ABCB Variations Conference; and</li><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_4ec75c12-a8e0-4011-af99-1fd5ca155c59"><title id="_32226049-1911-4376-be7b-a0f53b49240b">BCA 96 Amendment No. 4</title><p>Amendment No. 4 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 4 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul><p>Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_07c4e96a-beb1-4d12-b62e-2a03f2601774"><title id="_64c4612f-bb4e-451d-8399-90fdfa71714e">BCA 96 Amendment No. 5</title><p>Amendment No. 5 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 5 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>include minor technical changes; and</li><li>amend clauses to improve clarity and to reduce the possibility of differences in interpretation; and</li><li>expand on the requirements for subfloor ventilation based on climatic conditions.</li></ul><p>Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_1d55ce33-260c-4abf-b0c0-07f597234d3d"><title id="_1fa81db4-b290-4f4e-8d36-6b8adaf640f4">BCA 96 Amendment No. 6</title><p>Amendment No. 6 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 6 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>expand on the requirements for carparking for people with disabilities; and</li><li>replace Sound Transmission Class (STC) with weighted sound reduction index (R<sub id="_1e49d0e2-d69f-45f0-ba8c-5023046f2cc1">w</sub>) within <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/60_0.15.0.xml#_7d254556-c9e5-4c2f-8f7e-b1acec56d6cc" id="_5548024e-b04c-4aeb-b0a7-4c664dbaeebd" scope="local" type="part">Part F5</xref>; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul><p>Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_4633bf9f-11ea-4de3-abb8-401793d20bd8"><title id="_d9272168-29b2-4b4e-916d-46be15b11ac2">BCA 96 Amendment No. 7</title><p>Amendment No. 7 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 7 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>include requirements for non-required and private stairways; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul><p>Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_633aaba1-6273-48d9-8d0f-6630e9824584"><title id="_133d30f2-8fe7-4765-90b4-1af5cd786d0b">BCA 96 Amendment No. 8</title><p>Amendment No. 8 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 8 is to—update references to Standards; and</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>include minor technical changes; and</li><li>achieve greater consistency between both Volumes of the BCA for stairway construction.</li></ul><p>Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_7a9c759a-02b9-4862-baf2-c152aa7a0522"><title id="_a7f58ec4-79dd-496f-9630-8fb34ab0700e">BCA 96 Amendment No. 9</title><p>Amendment No. 9 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 9 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>include minor technical changes; and</li><li>clarify which glazed assemblies must comply with AS 2047 and which must comply with AS 1288.</li></ul><p>Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_c6c331e5-9eae-4e5e-8853-851f41d794ad"><title id="_518124e3-be74-4c25-b71c-1863e6223ba5">BCA 96 Amendment No. 10</title><p>Amendment No. 10 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 10 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>clarify that windows must comply with AS 2047 for resistance to water penetration; and</li><li>subject to certain conditions, allow a non-fire-isolated stairway to connect an additional storey; and</li><li>update signage required for people with disabilities, including the need for signs to contain Braille and tactile information; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul><p>Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_8a8c8d63-099e-4fd8-b23f-5e5b4a126a4a"><title id="_ce8339e3-19ca-43fa-8092-cdf11284e99e">BCA 96 Amendment No. 11</title><p>Amendment No. 11 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 11 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>transfer public policy matters, with respect to structural adequacy, from the AS 1170 series to the BCA; and</li><li>introduce Class 7a, 7b and 9c classifications; and</li><li>update the provisions for residential buildings used for the accommodation of the aged to align with the Commonwealth Aged Care Act, 1997; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul><p>Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_c1a5dd43-9c8c-4b03-92d7-da7a8ba699c7"><title id="_20f6d0c5-5560-40db-8896-bc3d08724a23">BCA 96 Amendment No. 12</title><p>Amendment No. 12 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 12 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>apply the swimming pool safety provisions to swimming pools associated with Class 4 parts as well as Class 2 and 3 buildings; and</li><li>allow the use of either the 1989 editions or the 2002 editions of the 1170 series of standards; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul><p>Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_16f20ad7-7859-4df5-8d69-b9208f200679"><title id="_2ed8cb2c-6d53-4d8e-8a8c-3e9e2347570b">BCA 96 Amendment No. 13</title><p>Amendment No. 13 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 13 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>reform the provisions for fire hazard properties of materials; and</li><li>revise a requirement for the use of non-combustible materials; and</li><li>include additional requirements for the protection of electrical switchboards which sustain electricity supply to emergency equipment; and</li><li>include minor changes to the requirements for aged care buildings; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul><p> Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_ea259c3f-7fe5-4f16-93ec-0c49c3fd239f"><title id="_01865bb9-6352-4a0e-98b4-cd38a85e915d">Adoption of BCA 2004 Volume One</title><p>The 2004 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of BCA 2004 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>update references from BCA 96 to BCA 2004; and</li><li>include a Performance Requirement considering human impact with glazing; and</li><li>reform the provisions for sound insulation; and</li><li>reform the maintenance provisions; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_7453317b-b783-49f1-a59c-c6cbb6b2c779"><title id="_8c97b714-f578-4516-b4f4-ad093cfe165d">Adoption of BCA 2005 Volume One</title><p>The 2005 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of BCA 2005 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>clarify when fire sprinklers are required to be installed in buildings; and</li><li>update the provisions for waterproofing of wet areas; and</li><li>include energy efficiency measures for Class 2 and 3 buildings and Class 4 parts; and</li><li>more closely align the requirements for lifts with those of Occupational Health and Safety legislation; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_34dc21d9-f096-421b-b9b5-48910df092eb"><title id="_6290bb4e-2b4c-4d21-8db3-94284ef6eea4">Adoption of BCA 2006 Volume One</title><p>The 2006 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of BCA 2006 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update schedule of referenced documents; and</li><li>include a national testing regime for cladding in cyclonic areas; and</li><li>withdraw of AS 1530.3 tests on floor materials and floor coverings and wall and ceiling linings; and</li><li>include energy efficiency measures for Class 5 to 9 buildings; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_7c8f0d0d-7506-4fcb-aa04-bb3f5b7c9c36"><title id="_cc35486b-86f5-46e0-b5d2-7fcc0f0e471a">Adoption of BCA 2007 Volume One</title><p>The 2007 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of BCA 2007 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>update energy efficiency provisions including providing additional information; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_dea5626a-2b76-4a9c-81b2-f0668d5de6f5"><title id="_f4fbb8b2-1180-4cef-89ab-4456dc8d569e">Adoption of BCA 2008 Volume One</title><p>The 2008 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of BCA 2008 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>due to changes in the types of detector now available, rather than only allowing the use of a heat detectors when smoke detector would be unsuitable in the atmosphere, to allow the use of any type of detector deemed suitable by AS 1670.1; and</li><li>clarify the intent of the BCA when a service penetrates a building element required to have an FRL; and</li><li>amend the requirements for door handle heights to be consistent with AS 1428.1; and</li><li>align some BCA terms with current industry terminology; and</li><li>include lists of other Commonwealth, State and Territory legislation affecting buildings; and</li><li>include suitable provisions for swimming pool water recirculation systems; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_c17c3a23-952f-44a5-b0a5-5c69ada1e426"><title id="_3dbbff08-23d5-4134-9448-06f091732e8a">Adoption of BCA 2009 Volume One</title><p>The 2009 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of BCA 2009 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>after expiry of the agreed transition period, except for the 1993 edition of AS 1170.4, delete all references to the older loading standards contained in the AS 1170 series and consequently, all provisions referring to them; and</li><li>clarify the application of the vertical separation provisions; and</li><li>clarify the intent of separation of equipment; and</li><li>simplify the wire balustrade provisions, including the addition of a Verification Method; and</li><li>clarify the provisions for the construction of sanitary compartments to enable an unconscious occupant to be removed; and</li><li>clarify the height of rooms in an attic and with a sloping ceiling; and</li><li>further update the energy efficiency provisions; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_55127b09-081e-474b-9cdf-98b085a8848d"><title id="_fa7110e6-98b3-4caa-9c17-c380c8631710">Adoption of BCA 2010 Volume One</title><p>The 2010 edition of the BCA Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of BCA 2010 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>delete reference to the 1993 edition of AS 1170.4 and consequently all provisions referring to it; and</li><li>increase the stringency of the energy efficiency provisions and, as part of reducing greenhouse gas emissions, introduce provisions for the greenhouse gas intensity of the energy source for services such as water and space heaters; and</li><li>update <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/5e2c1f63-e589-4ce1-95e8-5c3e286a7aff/94_0.11.0.xml#_f2160260-95a1-4c0e-bfa2-099fdad1ca4e" id="_52229b87-14dc-4ec1-93af-9a0483852fe2" scope="local" type="part">Part G5</xref>, as a consequence of referencing the 2009 edition of AS 3959 construction in bushfire-prone areas, to include provisions which apply to a Class 10a building or deck associated with a Class 2 or 3 building located in a designated bushfire prone area; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_bb065995-4a33-47c8-81ba-07dc35b0d348"><title id="_654ff4f7-f748-4b22-a512-3fb45f302e8a">Adoption of NCC 2011 Volume One</title><p>The 2011 edition of the NCC Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of NCC 2011 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>align the NCC with the Access Code in the Disability (Access to Premises — Buildings) Standards; and</li><li>restructure the fire hazard property provisions; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_dcd7564a-1d66-4429-bccd-ca3ebf04ebb8"><title id="_170a1cb2-604e-470c-b554-e453ac887b12">Adoption of NCC 2012 Volume One</title><p>The 2012 edition of the NCC Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of NCC 2012 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>include revised provisions aimed at reducing slips, trips and falls in buildings; and</li><li>include a Verification Method for emergency lighting; and</li><li>align the NCC with changes to the National Quality Standard for early childhood education and care; and</li><li>include exemptions for Class 8 electricity network substations; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_d27c3e37-458e-44b6-b5ba-58a9006d817e"><title id="_ced91bc1-4946-4472-a62d-06f4c649be8c">Adoption of NCC 2013 Volume One</title><p>The 2013 edition of the NCC Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of NCC 2013 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>include new provisions for openable windows to reduce falls in buildings; and</li><li>include a Performance Requirement and reference a Standard for construction in flood hazard areas; and</li><li>consolidate the building related components of the AS 1735 lift series into the BCA; and</li><li>enhance the egress provisions for people with disability; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_ec037c8e-59c4-442a-9930-2aaefa5be229"><title id="_1b581be8-69fc-47df-bccf-cb2a71e926c0">Adoption of NCC 2014 Volume One</title><p>The 2014 edition of the NCC Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of NCC 2014 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>quantify slip resistance on ramps, stairways and landings; and</li><li>include provisions for photoluminescent exit signs; and</li><li>expand the fire-resistance concession for timber-framed construction to include Class 3 buildings; and</li><li>remove the requirement for fire hose reels in a Class 2 or Class 3 building or a Class 4 part of a building; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_c090ef94-74d3-4a1d-937e-9d1b124a753d"><title id="_4ba2e2cc-281d-49bc-82dc-70d37c0de5b3">Adoption of NCC 2015 Volume One</title><p>The 2015 edition of the NCC Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of NCC 2015 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>include a Verification Method for structural reliability; and</li><li>improve the usability of the barrier provisions; and</li><li>expand the requirements for sprinkler protection to aged care buildings; and</li><li>include a Verification Method for weatherproofing of external walls; and</li><li>improve the usability of energy efficiency provisions for air-conditioning and ventilation systems.</li></ul></section><section id="_250a5335-1a83-4824-bf82-213d2701d06d"><title id="_ded9f649-b5e5-4831-8de7-0e8d6fe0b520">Adoption of NCC 2016 Volume One</title><p>The 2016 edition of NCC Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of NCC 2016 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>amend the “Introduction” and “General Requirements” as part of the initiative to increase the use of Performance Solutions; and</li><li>include new Verification Methods for structural robustness and indoor air quality; and</li><li>include provisions for fire-protected timber; and</li><li>include requirements for farm-type buildings; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_31f3d86d-a419-4a32-b0e1-996fae3be5d6"><title id="_4eb7ab80-f537-44be-b2a8-5916b3d2096e">NCC 2016 Volume One Amendment No. 1</title><p>Amendment No. 1 to the 2016 edition of NCC Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 1 is to—</p><ul><li>introduce a new Verification method, CV3, for limiting fire spread via external wall assemblies; and</li><li>include reference to the revised edition of AS 2118.1; and</li><li>clarify provisions relating to the use of external wall claddings and attachments; and</li><li>revise the evidence of suitability provisions.</li></ul></section><section id="_71a7cc88-ed75-45fa-b0f6-63fdb96f967d"><title id="_33e47389-03c8-486f-87c9-6f52f29a09c9">Adoption of NCC 2019 Volume One </title><p>The 2019 edition of NCC Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of NCC 2019 Volume One is to—</p><ul><li>include the Governing Requirements, that result from revision of Section A to improve readability and are common to all NCC volumes; and</li><li>introduce the use of schedules that are common to all NCC volumes; and</li><li>include new Verification Methods, including the Fire Safety Verification Method; and</li><li>clarify provisions, including provisions relating to measurement of distance between required alternative exits; and</li><li>expand the requirements for sprinkler protection to residential buildings; and</li><li>introduce requirements for accessible adult change facilities; and</li><li>introduce requirements for management of water vapour and condensation; and</li><li>introduce requirements for occupiable outdoor areas; and</li><li>increase stringency of energy efficiency requirements; and</li><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_d253d935-9f53-44ff-ba8d-484d21091a8d"><title id="_9fa898ec-f4ed-4c6a-8c05-29a09fea64fc">NCC 2019 Amendment No. 1</title><p>Amendment No. 1 to the 2019 edition of NCC Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 1 is to—</p><ul><li>require that a process be followed to improve the quality of and documentation for Performance Solutions; and</li><li>include a new provision regarding egress from early childhood centres; and</li><li>require labelling of Aluminium Composite Panels; and</li><li>clarify the concession that permits timber framing for low-rise Class 2 and 3 buildings.</li></ul></section><section id="_831989f4-ca10-4271-b509-105650c49de2"><title id="_ad3ddc0a-93c7-4b12-a455-62e92318b8bc">NCC 2022</title><p>The 2022 edition of NCC Volume One was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of NCC Volume One 2022 is to—</p><ul><li>include quantified Performance Requirements; and</li><li>clarify and improve provisions relating to fire performance of building elements, including external walls; and</li><li>include provisions to improve fire safety for early childhood centres and primary schools; and</li><li>include expanded weatherproofing and waterproofing provisions; and</li><li>include bushfire protection requirements for certain Class 9 buildings; and</li><li>incorporate amended energy efficiency provisions; and</li><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>include other minor technical changes.</li></ul></section></page>