<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause"?><clause id="_bda87319-45f9-4a41-b7d3-f56f99083845" outputclass="ncc-clause" variation="NT"><meta><facet building="Class 1a"/><facet building="Class 1b"/><facet building="Class 4"/><facet building="Class 5"/><facet building="Class 6"/><facet building="Class 7a"/><facet building="Class 7b"/><facet building="Class 8"/><facet building="Class 9a"/><facet building="Class 9b"/><facet building="Class 10a"/><facet building="Class 10b"/><facet building="Class 10c"/></meta><sptc>S28C3</sptc><title id="_c60e2296-c3c2-43b5-a599-cf8e9c1af048">R<sub xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_26c15003-b677-496d-a18a-7840dcd7f88c" inv:access="external">W</sub> applicable to construction</title><archive-num>2019: NT Spec F5.2: Table 2</archive-num><subclause id="_77b0c87f-981f-4ac0-b41d-c2d240f12169" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_aad98eb6-20e7-43cc-8b2b-5f065dfaf63f">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p>Construction in accordance with the following has an R<sup xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_324eb5fb-a1cd-4fcf-8da5-fcec177470e6" inv:access="external"><sub id="_a142cbae-a311-467f-883c-8dc6cd994dd0" inv:access="external">W</sub></sup> of not less than 45:</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_6e9ea2f7-4ec0-40c2-bc3a-ae75a2bc029c">Walls — clay brickwork:<ol><li id="_7047ce03-687a-4f5d-84d5-b3d204322c16">230 mm thick in one or more leaves and with a mass per unit area of not less than 290 kg/m<sup xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_f1862ddb-11b1-4c56-9a79-132c9707a801" inv:access="external">2</sup>.</li><li>110 mm thick rendered 13 mm thick on both sides with a mass per unit area of the unrendered wall being not less than 190 kg/m<sup xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_00e03bae-d65e-48a4-b5ef-2f19dafb3642" inv:access="external">2</sup>.</li><li>110 mm thick, of semi-dry-pressed bricks and rendering 13 mm on one side, the mass per unit area being not less than 215 kg/m<sup xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_efb3acde-1f75-453a-a944-b2c3652681e6" inv:access="external">2</sup>.</li><li>110 mm thick, of extruded brick and rendered 13 mm on one side, the mass per unit area being not less than 180 kg/m<sup xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_cd031bf9-3b02-4b88-a317-1b2e088cedaf" inv:access="external">2</sup>.</li></ol></li><li id="_df57cc80-2631-451d-900f-78139f36b7e7">Walls — concrete brickwork: 110 mm thick with a mass per unit area of not less than 195 kg/m<sup xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_8131ad3b-9e87-48b6-9457-1e2de744c81c" inv:access="external">2</sup>.</li><li id="_74785837-7178-4c34-ab15-e8ef2716561d">Walls — concrete blockwork:<ol><li id="_f552e8fa-4b1a-4e42-b6a9-f092756c7a70">190 mm thick with a mass per unit area of not less than 215 kg/m<sup xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_e2d7f908-c2d0-4be4-b33a-659653134fea" inv:access="external">2</sup>.</li><li>140 mm thick, the wall thickness of the blocks being not less than 44 mm and with—<ol><li>50 mm x 50 mm timber battens spaced at not more than 610 mm centres screw-fixed on one face of the blocks into resilient plugs with rubber inserts between the battens and the wall; and</li><li>the face of the battens clad with 13 mm thick standard plasterboard; and</li><li>a mass per unit area of the whole system of not less than 220 kg/m<sup xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_00a40e9b-d8f7-4c50-8bb2-74960579c163" inv:access="external">2</sup>.</li></ol></li></ol></li><li id="_9f89601c-5b24-48dd-ac10-1e3eda80aec8">Walls — concrete:<ol><li id="_6c363a59-f002-4c38-bd6f-0b109710c904">In-situ concrete — 125 mm thick and with a density of not less than 2200 kg/m<sup xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_fcd82ec5-0217-476d-9f06-430602ed4256" inv:access="external">3</sup>.</li><li>In-situ concrete — 100 mm thick and with a density of not less than 2500 kg/m<sup xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_874a08ee-1fba-4aa1-ba9e-b7228d95dd8f" inv:access="external">3</sup>.</li><li>Precast concrete — 100 mm thick and without joints.</li></ol></li><li id="_749474f1-70d4-457e-98e9-5e331a66b2a0">Walls — steel stud walling:<ol><li id="_a9bbd24a-2d96-4379-b29b-425800a37ba3">With 2 layers of 16 mm thick fire-protective grade plasterboard fixed to each face.</li><li>With—<ol><li>1 layer of 13 mm thick fire-protective grade plasterboard fixed to one face, and before fixing, 50 mm thick mineral or glass wool blanket or batts stapled to the back of each sheet so that the sheet is completely covered; and</li><li>2 layers of 13 mm thick fire-protective grade plasterboard fixed to the other face.</li></ol></li><li>With—<ol><li>1 layer of 16 mm thick fire-protective grade plasterboard fixed to one face; and</li><li>50 mm thick mineral or glass wool blanket or batts wedged firmly between the studs; and</li><li>2 layers of fire-protective grade plasterboard fixed to the other face, the inner layer being 16 mm thick and the outer layer being 13 mm.</li></ol></li><li>With 2 layers of 13 mm plasterboard on both sides of 75 mm studs.</li></ol></li><li id="_80aef1b2-0d30-42b0-9eed-a35417e03770">Floors — concrete:<ol><li id="_d8110e0b-ed1b-4b67-a12a-0c9307010d8c">In-situ concrete slab — 125 mm thick and with a density of not less than 2200 kg/m<sup xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_ae7b6c07-7fd2-406b-ada9-4cc6b0d72fb1" inv:access="external">3</sup>.</li><li>In-situ concrete slab — 100 mm thick and with a density of not less than 2500 kg/m<sup xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_c3d9a5e5-cb10-4edc-ae43-98d8814e5306" inv:access="external">3</sup>.</li><li>Pre-cast concrete slab — 100 mm thick and without joints.</li></ol></li><li id="_b74e42ca-1b13-463b-8ce9-ac4f33101553">Floors — timber, comprising—<ol><li id="_5a978fd2-01a5-4f2f-9547-96b2380197a5">timber joists not less than 175 mm x 50 mm; and</li><li>75 mm thick mineral or glass wool blanket or batts cut to fit tightly between joists and laid on 10 mm thick plasterboard fixed to underside of joists; and</li><li>25 mm thick mineral or glass wool blanket or batts laid over entire floor, including tops of joists before flooring is laid; and</li><li>tongued and grooved boards not less than 19 mm thick, secured to 75 mm x 50 mm battens; and</li><li>the assembled flooring laid over the joists, but not fixed to them, with the battens lying between the joists.</li></ol></li></ol></subclause><subclause id="_bdd281cf-7f77-4a0c-9fe2-49286ce8f415" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_a513836c-b5fa-47e4-a518-c9d8508eb95c">SubClause</title><num>2</num><p>Ducts or other construction separating soil and waste pipes from units, constructed in accordance with the following, have an R<sub xmlns:inv="urn:xpressauthor:xpressdocument" id="_b2b497c0-b87b-43ff-ba31-1149a1a08eb1" inv:access="external">W</sub> of not less than 30:</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_02f6fb42-8af1-41f1-b175-68c4e3742927">Masonry — not less than 90 mm thick.</li><li id="_8965a053-1c1b-425b-bdf8-cc1885a8b973">Plasterboard — 2 layers of plasterboard:<ol><li id="_42626f47-3a2f-4f4b-99f6-11455ecf7991">Each 10 mm thick, fixed to timber studs not less than 75 mm x 50 mm and spaced at not more than 400 mm centres.</li><li>Each 13 mm thick, one on each side of steel studs not less than 50 mm deep and spaced at not more than 400 mm centres.</li></ol></li></ol></subclause></clause>